So, what do we talk about...there we go
so what we want to talk about today is what exactly are
...what we refer to these modern services there's quite a lot ofand,
then we want pretty much just jumping to demos and show you what we've been working on so
that we can improve the collection and connection to those services so first
of all what exactly are modern services now maybe you're probably
using things like sequel server or some kind of caching technologies?
Those are services.
So, in many ways we're not talking about a fundamental change.
It's really an evolution of those technical services that you
may be using which you guys probably have a lot of choice in but what's happening is the
levels of expectations for what people can deliver for instance like
a serum system and something I might install of like quickbooks or something of
the years past a greatly and improved greatly
...expectations are higher...companies like sales force that just come in
and just blow away all the expectations of what you think you might be
...and you now you want to be able to connect to that.
So, there's an evolution of the business services as well
Customer to resource to other management of
...of materials and that's what we want to be
able to support what we're seeing...is you know,
a lot of these services on here...kind of business-oriented it used to be
the most active services on the web or kind of consumer focus.
Using sales force or api is really important to us how important we
do seventy five billion transactions a month overall on the
...first platform six fifty five percent of those are through our api
...services through integration now and for historically too long
period of time there hasn't been some really great tooling in the first-class id
...to make that samples so this is an important thing for businesses to be able to
bring this and make it simple for developers to use and one of the challenges
...if you remember years ago because we've actually been around for a wildness tooling space
there was this, you know, xml web service idea and if everybody would just
builder services the same we would have this common tooling paradigm and you'd be able to connect to them
it was really easy, yeah, right but, unfortunately things don't stay still.
Things are continually evolving and the idea that
we could continually keep up with that is just an unrealistic expectation
I was joke about chasing rabbits are chickens I'm not so what you're supposed to chase but whatever it
is that complicated so when we were challenge to come up with a better tool
you experience what things we...just not worth trying
to get everybody to abide by a single standard because whenever a standard is complete it
is now legacy so we thought about all these different technologies that are
out there and sales...you know,...new as a relatively new as a company
...the service businesses even they've got a quick evolution I mean
you've got what...services you guys support now what kind of service letting the technologies
right well since, you know, sales forces as a platform has you know,
web presentation services we've got business logic services
we've got consumer facing website services with her roku right but,
the technologies so the technologies behind them from a developer standpoint,
you know, we have you're going to...actually you want
see something different so we used to be on and we kept this part of our demo and what I would
do is show you are whittle generation page and there's probably a dozen different was
those in there and that doesn't even represent all the soap and points that we have
or sorry rest endpoints that we have things like metadata api
stood discover what you built on the platform what we've got
streaming api so that you can do real-time integrations with the data
what we've got a streaming api metadata api
...bulk data api so
you can transfer millions of rows of data in and out of the platform it goes on and on
an average of these are going to be the same technology they just they can't they can't because,
because today
soap doesn't work because we're talking mobile and we're talking about like very much smaller
interactions so it's great for bowl but today rest is become more important but even arrest
there's variations and then there's authentication variations that go in there and yes there's
all off standard but,
you know, for two people have been working in this and trying to
implemented there are so many variations that it just becomes
very difficult so when you are consuming one of these modern services
is a multi-step process first of all just to
...this service if I want to consumes sales force
someone just send-me the url user name and password I had to go to sales
...and say I would like to consumer service I need to configure
this service to be able to do that sales force has to...any services
...you go create an app on facebook you do the same thing on sales...you get consumer key all that kind
of stuff so there's that first step right?
There is the next step of once I consume it what is the url right we had
...the one notes...the...and the
...notes of all urls...maybe you have to of remember what they are but...
inverted the concept now instead of having to know url.
But, if I just use my identity discover.
Active consumed it if you remember with ad service reference and the
...single file generator technologies that we had what.
Was the code what is the code that I...
...david kind of go through a little bit as well and how much of that should I have to
consume?
...after I've consumed at all well then why you've gotten
this ad service reference you've done was experiences you...code your project...now I go to the
worldwide web to go find eighteen different ways of people's opinion around how to
...so these are some of the problems that we want to undertake?
So, we went out and we talked to some of our customers around who's using
this was asking earlier and we have a customer land desk
...been a great customer that been willing to share their code of what they've gone through the
pains they've gone through and they've got a pretty cool scenario so
...desk is basicallya systems management company they do
device management they've got lots of different software solutions as well and,
they are software company turns out they have some bugs like the rest
of us a linear way to triage those bugs.
So, that turns out they also use sales force.
So, they've got their bugs and t fs and they can go and
buy qb triage team and described and all you know, the
new modern ways of managing bugs but the end of the day it's a wall
of bugs and somebody has to decide what's the...one in pry to...you know,
becomes the argument of the one I really like to work on or whatever it turns out that's not
exactly the most productive way to actually...customers.
So, they happen to use sales force and turns out they have some pretty important
dated sales words that actually works for them so,
what land ask is doing is they're using ...our customer support
offering which has a case object so cases like a customer support
instance and their time
vt fs bugs to sales force cases are naturally connected
to contacts and accounts so now they have more information about that bug
right at their fingertips...sales...so they will know?
How many customers are affected by a particular bug?
The big customers are spending lots of money with them maybe it's a deal
that's pending they will know what bugs are affected by them so they can utilize all
that information so now they can prioritize that and
...this is crazy right so they were trying to figure out how
do they visualize that so this is that give credit to the of a tanner from
...as they were basically use this population growth formula and what they were
trying to do is not just have this linear scale but try to make sure
that the important bugs got the top...didn't bury the medium bugs so it turns out to be
an interesting formula that they implemented the sample will be out on I get have
repo so be able to get access to this as well but it's pretty cool about what they're
doing is they're using the to data sources and creating what they call and
...score or unify metric priority?
We'll see this...place.
So, now
that they can do this calculation now they can get a visualization you
can see that curve going on there looking at their bugs.
They can drill into the bugs to see what customers are affected by the cases and
now the triage team
is off having a good old-time having their own party maybe having some
...because they're actually celebrating their...right
there developers for happy I'm happy developers happy developers make happy
customers so that's the case that we will walk through here so with vat
we will switch over to our demos this one here.
And, let's see so but, so, here we have the
...desk...of what they...they use is just...if we click
...anything it will not have much functionality because that quite honestly is
are demo is to put the services behind the functionality, yeah, so,
this is basically of the outline or
the user interface that we might have gotten from our ux the neighbor,
you know, one are you access trust so it's our job then to plumb this thing up
...plumbing in it to make it all work so let's start with adding sales force
...jump right into it so,
here we are in side of visual
studio and as a dot net developer or somebody who's unfamiliar sales
force the challenge that first
...is where do I start how do I do this what's available to me
so we know that within visual studio we've got a couple options around ad service reference so,
on sales force does have whittle definition
so may not be your first choice but like if it's the only thing available maybe
you go there so let me just show you what that's like?
So, I'm going-to go ahead and add service reference now one thing I understand about the
...first platform is that everything including your was though which is actually valuable data
because it describes the data that your storing is behind a login so it turns out that
...service reference actually doesn't work very well with
...to begin with all off...really the private loses the...so, it turns
out I happen to know that the next thing you want to do is go to advance?
Because service isn't going to work for me so I'll go to advanced and
...adam web reference now notice that were already like three dialogues
and at this point and, again, it's asking over a url times
...and maybe it's a spiral of death but so,
I could inner url here but then I'd be required...authenticate log in a salesperson there's
no mechanism for that in here luckily I found out that you can actually download
the whistles of file put it on your file system and then go ahead and
...that way so this is one of the first examples of even if we
support the technology for in this case open was
dol the authentication of evolved and we thought about
evolving this dialog and continuing to figure audio off patterns we just couldn't it
...we maintain able to this is one of the challenges okay so it was able to parse my was
they'll and is now generating a nice proxy class for me
I'm going-to go ahead and?
Show hidden files and what I want to do is I want to show you the
result of this I think you're probably already kind of getting the gist just by my
scrolling there if I open this reference about cs?
This is my clients this is what I'm supposed
to use to get those cases in contacts for land desk.
There's a couple of interesting things about it one
it doesn't allow you to step through with the debug so if you do have some kind of weird connectivity
...you have to know that this is there and remove it another,
another issue with this is you see this little slider...slider thing because kind of
...rarely grab it that's because there are
one hundred eighteen thousand lines of code in this
wisdom to get to contacts in cases.
Which I think is?
Just like as a proud developer you don't need all that
...who gets caught who gets paid the amount of code that they right.
Now this is a feature...trying to get you more money.
... one final negative of this also this is a generated file so if I did go in
and make some changes the next time that I had to refresh the whittle from
the service my changes would be lost we told you at the top donate don't touch this,
it says is...the very top-down texas and, there's a good reason for that so we're not going to go that way
...just delete that and then clean-up this web references folder.
So, there's another way to do this is I'm sure, you know,
being developers we could certainly create an http request we could figure out the
...off...rest it's easy it's rest
rated solvable rest and points and then go find the documentation and see what
the resulting shape of the data looks like the graph if you will
or I could go and see if I can find something on new get where's my.
I could go out and...do a search for sales force that seems reasonable new get is the new hot
...right everybody's got a new get
...the new in pm or the olympian of windows so anyways so,
that returns some results but there's a problem with this if I'm not familiar I don't want
to teach you guys to be the sales
force developer experts I just want to help you get your job done you don't know which one of these
...appropriate right this one right here
...pointing at that's actually only for universal lapse.
This one here says something about soap helpers I'm not sure it's exactly
right but then if I scroll down then I really start to get lost right I'm not sure what to
use so we're not going to do that either so it's nice
...you get has all these packages but there's no context.
...we've got a project open here there's no filtering to be able to support you
to give you context of...right so instead we're going to go to
add connected service is right there in the middle between the two and it turns out that
...in between those two other options that we didn't want and,
The connected service brings up this dialog of various services that you can connect
...explain a little bit more about this so this is what we've...envisioned on how we want to
connect to services rather than expect the world to come to us new world we kind of
taken this true and now we want to do is provide a cure rated list of
services instead of having have a one-size-fits-all we want to be able to
allow the uniqueness of each service and including
the ability to build on this over time so you see in the bottom left is
find more services you can go...the gallery and get more and will
...some of that moment in fact we have our friends at data logics that are building
pdf service as well so we want to provide
...extensibility model that would be
cater to those services and then you could consume those in that fashion like we'll see
what sales force...we get one thing I wanted to point out about, you know, whether it's appropriate for
what you're doing is you can see that...service has this download
cloud and says project support this project is currently
supported where this one is an obviously that one's for mobile and
...nbc web out so let's go ahead and we have that extra context
...provide here so let's walk through this now the process for connecting to the
...is first of all we gotta figure out or establish a
Credential authentication because what's going to happen is as we go through this we're
going to want to query the sales force a platform
for information at design-time so that means that basically what we're going
to do is going to turn visual studio into an api client for sales
...using these credentials and, you know, if you look at this is
not a generic dialogue write the very much is sales forces
got the sales was logo it's going to sales force layout it happens to be a wizard
flow...there's actually a very good point as soon as I selected
...configure that the code transferred over to sales force
developed code now this was developed
in conjunction with sales force we partnered on this big-shot out to the guys in fargo but,
this is that this is code where responsible for that's plugging in to
the connected services framework so I'm going to select the user account and,
environment I'm using a
custom domain name which will understand the reason for later on in the talk.
Once I once I've put that information and now we want to know what kind of
application you building we might assume that
it's web server flow but it doesn't have to work that way and, the two that we support right now for
...web server and...and password flow
off to has four or five different types of...depending on where your codes
running so you wouldn't use either of these if you're on a device for instance
the reason is there's no call back url on a device so there's
other mechanisms for that so we're going to go with a web server flow and then again,
very custom the sales forces the question about a branded sign in a
sign in page so our customers really do a lot of customizations
sometimes they like to completely wipe sales force the word off of
everything that they've implemented which is fine with us and one way they want to do that is in
the url so they can create a custom domain and then if they have a
...name they can do some mapping there and it just disappears completely so we're
...go ahead and do one of these...so I just another point is what
...see there's were remembering previous selections we've got mr use and
...this is a principle that we like for people building connected services because
we want use developers to not hacker remember and copy and paste in all...really want
to be able to select from for instance the list of objects that are available
...violators, you know, I've configured my design-time
...my runtime authentication and now what objects do I
want to have available to me and my projects and uninvolved
...you can see that no we don't want them all that was though but that...we'll?
...just in case you wanted them no, they don't have to worry about that so I want to contact and I want
to case so I can select those and then click finish.
Now what's interesting is this is still acting as a
...api client for sales force in that
...creating that configuration piece so instead of going
this sales force and saying hey I want to create a new all...off app and,
get my client id and secret were able to do that through the api at this point
so creates a new connected app which is the or configuration?
So, you never know moi.
Creates...and then leverages that the next thing it
does a scaffold up a bunch of stuff in there and will point out some more that?
So, this is part of being a connected service provider sorry,
... like that...is microsoft has some suggestions about
the flow and one of the philosophy
is of course is okay I've added your service one-way might
...what you do my project priority one but what do I do next priority
too so here's the things that have happened to this particular project
what we've added in web can fig the name of the connected app where the
off stuff that we created on the sales for side so that
you can reference that if you ever need to and, then we added some new get
the package references source still using new...so we're still using new get but we're using
were following the instructions of the service the...
prescriptive guidance to get you started some dot net references so that we can speak to the
speak to an external service and then the connection class the other thing that we
did was we took all that co-author information we stuck that and the web
...for-you so, that's already to go one of the
great things that I like about this is we created this thing missive...scroll
in here zooming and is this part here that says sales force
co-author redirect handler so this thing is awesome
because what that does now is it means that we've already given you all that off
stuff so that you don't have to worry about any of it you just exercise the
references in the toolkits we put in there and the whole dance is taken care
...saving of tokens obtaining
refresh tokens handling the scope all of that stuff is there for you so that's kinda cool?
Right so.
Let's go back to...
Right yeah,...the getting started that's the next thing that...so once you've
done this especially if it's the first-time it's like well okay I'm in my nbc app how do
I use this so we've got to walk throughs one for an nbc app and one for consul
...and I'm just going to start building this and I'm going to do it by selecting all the
code in here and creating a controller.
So, this was one...other principles that we have is we didn't want to pollute your project
was sample code.
Active use this for the fourth or fifth time we didn't want the first thing you do is delete class...
We wanted to be productive over time so instead of putting sample
code in the project we put it on a web page so next time you do this you
probably don't want that so here's the...empty controller that I'm going to create I'm going to color contacts.
And, then go ahead and add...
...standard nbc stuff
...standard nbc's stuff I'm going to just delete that because I'm going to use what
I copied from the getting started.
And, then and, you'll notice a whole bunch of red here well that's because I'm copying and pasting this
is a part of the scaffolding otherwise we know the context a little bit better the point here
is that my namespaces different so my name space should be the land...so,
I'm going to see if I have a fancier automatic it's awesome like...of
...strokes right so I'll see that now I've got a working
...now with in this controller are all
the methods for getting a list of contacts?
Creating contact updating contacts in the
leading contact so it's all represented in that piece of sample code and
it really doesn't change no matter what kind of object that you're dealing with...basic
...really representative...mapped into the mdc actions so that's pretty cool though for instance,
you know, there's, there's the index which will return a list of stuff ok so,
the next thing I'm going to do is
start creating the user interface for the contacts and I'm going to do that and,
this is one of my favorite parts of visual studio is...contextual...
Enough that's a word...made them up before goingtechnologies michael make-up words but, just,
you know,
the way that it handles the right click...to modifier for where you are and what you're doing
is really cool I think but anyways so, what to do is I'm going to create a list use the
list template and then for the model class?
I'm going to use the contact model that was scaffold inform
me so it's hard to see on the screen but there's a case there and then there's a contact
there and those were part of the connected
service wizard that we went through so select contact an ad that guy.
So, there's my view one thing I do want to do a little bit differently
is you'll notice that I've got every single.
In field that's on that contact in here I don't want that I really only
want like a half a dozen so what I'm going to do is cheap.
come over here and ...some views that are pre created there's nothing magic about these is
...the same as the ones in the walk through.
...down the field just to make the demo...all grab this and drop it
into my contacts views folder I'm going to replace and
update my window so there's, there's a half-dozen fields otherwise it's the same.
So, at this point and we're going to go I think I'm
going to go so we'll do a control f five.
To keep our fingers crossed.
Actually I'm pretty confident this is going to work you'll.
Throw stuff...a that these ok sales
first contacts and boom instantly ...authenticate using o
off is that off dance and we've...scaffold the code into your project
...libraries that we use but there's also scaffolding because while we have
some default code that we put in there we know depending on your scenario you might need to tweak a little bit.
Ok, so, as part of...off...assed were
presented with a we think you're this person here's the access that
your granting this application to on your service side you want to let that happen or not
so we'll say allow and sure enough we have
...contacts.
Now that didn't
require a really deep knowledge of exercising the sales force rest api and that's what I
think the real our of connected services comes in so let's go ahead and take a look
at there's a lot in that we created the connected app we consume did I
mean right there was that was far too long for me to figure out the first
...the connected service did that all for mathematical ok so if I click in...details I
can see the details of this of my details views working I can go ahead and try to edit this
guy I shouldn't be a problem but, one thing I want to point out which is kind
of cool is I'm going to make...first name ridiculously long and,
then when I tab added this...wasn't too happy
...comic jack so when I tab added this I've got a
field validation error it's telling me that the maximum amount for this field is forty
characters...saved that happy...code up any validation
rolla in of it is modern...you could do anything on a...click event okay well so,
what about an email for instance that's not a valid email again I've got a
school a validation all that says well that doesn't look like...email I'm not going...let you try to
say that so how...you do that okay well so I mentioned
that again I mention that thevisual studio is in itself
a client of our api in one of our api is called describe and
described says what is a request to get all
the information about that particular object and I should I should just pause for a
site when I talk about objects and you can think of them is tables the traditionally we don't call them
tables...a sales...idiosyncrasies but...any rate you can see that this
first object her first field here id it's been annotated with
...a display name and also that it's not create
able and not...data will because id user mutable on our platform
...ideas should be and all this information came from that
described now we happen to be able to do that but other services will have other
kind of special sauce that they can put on top so this was another example when we
were doing tooling around services we were working with
dynamic crm and we were trying to get their metadata
was working with sap were transfer how to get their meta data...was using o data
...part audio data board using custom annotations before data for was out and
what we realizes every service has this information but they have
...unique places and the...again the idea to get everybody to put in the same place
was unattainable so we decided to if it's and costs almost like a
...almost like taking a step back and going okay you guys start here rather than
start here and the way...service connected service can if you...all that it's in the
...so now in the you can sales
...the ui they can control where they go get their meta data sap can get their
meta data dynamic serum can get their meta data so here?
We've.
Generate the attributes just to be able based on that metadata we have a really nice
poker class yep so, yeah, and, in the interesting thing is the reason why we're able to get that
described data is the sales...types are not just primitives like you would see in
a standard database...types like phone email address url
so on which allows you to have this kind of rich represent meant
of the data outside of the sales...ui so we got sales...data yet we get sales
...data so what's the next so let's go get some bugs from visual studio online
...all right so the next service we want to get from
...so I'm going-to go over and say
...connect service now turns out we actually don't have one for
via vs online yet they're working on improving with
their rest api but I was working with the team and I was able to go and create a
...for this what you code...program all program manager
...a developer tools so we'd like to know our customers do so, anyway, so,
I did write this sample it again be on my repo you can get it by just going out
to the gallery and you can see the...online one I built there's the
...service that data logics is building so what we'll do is we will
...that one and again
or musical wizard here again but notice the wizard is slightly different it's
not just branding the pages are different from using the handy dandy
...selector so that's a user control and you
didn't even after that I didn't have to write this part of the controls able to...leverage it because it comes with the tty
...client so now I've got my
vs online project I can go in again I'm choosing
one-time author options in this case it's unique to...online?
I can name the thing that gets added to my project...I might actually consume
...multiple times.
And, now when I finish will do the same new get thing
we'll give you a same getting started...what happened what...projectand,
then some samples for some next steps so the next steps our to create a
controller...come over here and create a controller.
For work items.
To work items work item...
...singular...be my first break.
Right and, we will...to the fix-up.
And, I'll remove my little warning about that so now
you're seeing here is I've got a standard nbc comptroller but if we notice I've got a
select statement here and this is o data select because that's
what the hdf-eos online team is doing and was
...foresee use...use cycles so ...or
...one...since we have api for creating inserting data we
had we created a sql like language called...it's very much like
sequel there's only a select but, you know, that's what we call it soccer.
So, now...our view.
And, we'll make it a list view again.
And, it's on our work item type because we scaffold that in as well and you hear me
using the word scaffolding as opposed to generating we'll see that
...in a second here all right so at this point will
run this again so now we should be building up our services
...service consumption faq we're also building upper list of pages so
...clear little room here so we've got
...sales force contacts now we're going to get some work items
...to do and I didn't take the time that you did to clean-up
the list but you get the idea so now I've got data from sales
force get data from vs online now we want national
...and actually it's kinda funny
...talking about massive swim ajax first came out I don't know many years ago and
now we're talking about like serious business use case...line-of-business
...big mash potato all right so what I've got here is I've just
...speed things up a little bit...dragon some files and walk who's a little
bit groups not the whole thing just the one so, what
...mirrors my controllers folder...and, in here
what we see is they've got this boomed calculator which is what they're using so we need
to bring that in some ego grab that?
And, in our business folder what we'll see is?
That it's going to return a un p score result...just another model.
And, what's nice about this is.
Were grabbing this rest data we years
we're using the services to generate these models so that once I get the
services top populate models I get to take advantage of ala dot
net technologies so I can use link I can move these objects around I can select
and join and this is the shape of the object that I want to actually return.
Okay, so, let's actually want to do is close this up and we're going to build.
And, we get a list of errors and the first one is a
vs online ideas missing but I'm pretty sure sales forced I've we've got that custom field
in...object we created a custom field on
a case object specifically to hold the via some online id and there it is so,
we have a that rate but notice the field in or the
property name is underscore, underscore c okay so underscore, underscore
Idiosyncratic city of sales force it represents something that's custom in your
schema so could be a custom object...custom field we put
...see in their to prevent collisions with any
kind of sales force objects are fields that might be created later so really good way to
abstract but remember I mention scaffolding not
generating instead of having to do some magic which we invented all kinds
of great technologies in the languages to deal with generated code and how to
extend it partial classes and all kinds of stuff I
...able edit the code because we scaffold
it's yours to own so there's no magic its code that we...project with
its yours I just added a json property attribute and now I can clean-up so
in my code I can actually use a property that I want to use without having to create
yet another model object to copied and really the only way that you'll lose that
...is a view delete that file is no warning at the top
...can't touch this matter
ok so work on does not taken have a definition for case?
Ok, so, where does work item come from?
Vs online, yeah, so, a case comes from sales force
so here's another place where what I'm going to do is
...instead of having get other objects I'm just going to put the case property
...the work item object again...changing the
...code because it's my code and this is really cool because you're actually changing
or enhancing the schema where these things are not naturally related
write your creating relationship between and which is very and I also do like eighty thousand
lines of code and classes to do it so now it's asking for account you were you're supposed
at account you didn't tell me that I can fix that easily...okay, you want to do yeah,
I'm going to do it all right you broken you fix it it's the sales for side so yeah, what
I don't want to do is go through the whole connected services process again because
it does a lot more than I really want but what I want to do instead is update the
sales force data service and this was another key attributes that
we want to build we didn't want this to be demo fodder for pm stand-up behind going look at this great
feature we wanted you to be able to build on over time and that
iterative fashions so here's an example of we've implemented update on the sales
...connected service and, yeah, and, it actually runs through the same wizard but you can see
there's, there's things that I can't change what I can change is
when I get to the list of objects that I want to include and you can see
...visual studio magically knows that I've got a case
in the contact already inherits magic...and that's the thing is
...again tooling we used to store special...files which I
won't tell you what we actually column to remember this but in this case we want to look at your
code so we just use features like roslyn to look
in your project and if you have a type that matches the thing we're looking
at sales force go that's it so we just we're going to work over your
curfew deleted the case it would show up and you could re
added in other words or if you hand added it yourself or...and then and, finally
what happened there was all it did was scaffold that object for me because of area...service reference
...had a lot handler and the connected out so now I'm going to add the case sorry
the account object to case so now I have a
app that's a good all together I was able to
consume the service and I was able to scaffold the code
...able to enhance that code as relevant to meet for this particular
project so now I've got sales force contacts and will login here?
So, go get the contacts and for via so work items now
we'll get the work items and now we can make mash potatoes.
So, now what I'm seeing is the bugs from the sl.
Oops score
is calculated in this business class that goes and takes a look at the cases and figures
are all these cool calculations and gives us this score so.
So, for...
Now you're command-line guy
is that helpful the way it looks and just because I'm a command-line...I don't like pretty...so,
let's go fix that we have one more thing I want to do is I'm going to
A little api controller in here.
And, all this does is
...that same room calculation but it doesn't from and api web api
controller because in this case what I want to do is I want to take advantage of
candles controls orlando's to can
took advantage of condos controls to be fair.
And, now I can get and
...and what it we'll do is from the client?
Make a call to that same service and now I'm getting
a better visualization of my data and if I'm looking here
where's are we have that special outpost six
okay so if I look at this...a bug.
And, I can look at the bug in
...online I've got a login so here's an example of where
we're taking advantage of authentication but and
it's cool in fact it's somewhat cool but you'll notice I actually have...it doesn't it's a
...not click once if anybody knows what that means but anyway so,
now I can see my bug in various online and
I can also whoops we can also look at the case.
In sales force...in a sales force.
So, what's wrong with this...way let's enjoy the
goodness part first talon I got bugs
in vs online I got work cases in sales...I can see
them all apparently somebody's trying to open a datacenter and mars I
mean you talk about advancement...about chance and l so.
So, what is wrong with this application at this point?
Come on, evaluate what.
There's a lot of logins.
There's a lot of logins that's no good no that's not sticky.
Let's get out of this per second.
And,...close one...this one and now ...this
in again and you'll notice that well, actually I'm jumping...I'm not
going to do that for so the first part is what you may not have noticed is
the app itself is not actually...secure.
Actually was able to get to it wasn't until we started querying bugs and work
...from sales was that we got challenge for login now for those you that are implementing
off on your appshow you guys doing it you doing
it with sequel server as your authentication scheme having
get another copy of users somewhere and because that is the easy way of doing it and
franchises some...that there have always going to admit to it but we now
...know so it turns out to
...actually tried to use as your ad to...log authenticate...apps?
...anybody's been successful with it.
So, maybe it is difficult you need like the
...by your side and he so he was by our
side and we've worked through improving that experience
so now I don't want yet another sequel database of users land
desk has ad that's where...employees are logging in...take advantage of that so I'm going to
...here and the configure as your ad
connected service lets me configure my project it's
not just consuming data services and this case we're
...consume authentication services so we'll go off and we will
finish configuring this and what this one's going to do
is go out to as your ad very similar to what we did in sales...we...to create
a connected app it's going to create and as your...
And, that's the thing that manages the permissions for all the
resources.
Does this web app have permission to access as
your ad can I use my as
your ad identity's to authenticate users and what we've also
done and this is the one thing we did behind-the-scenes is we set
up single sign on between as your
...and sales force now I just...say one thing,
you know, you guys are watching the screen is he was talking and you saw a
lot of stuff going on in their array that represents kind of?
Knowledge base that you get to tap into
and completely leverage right so that's one of my favorite ones...because there's just
...launching configured for-you in the back-end we have this kind of feeling
that if you understand authentication...we've done wrong that's not secure right that's a that's
a breach so right so we have the same mott pattern here we have what happened
to your project next steps getting started we follows
principles again but now if we run this again and I'm just going to
do one little thing here.
Going to run this again and now what
esri the configure audrey d did was it knowledge consume the new
gets and scaffold stuff...my project and wed and added to
in using roslyn because it's your code.
We...found on your controllers and we added the authorize attribute to it
so now everything in the app is now secure.
Of course it was scaffolds you can go changed if...parts of the site that you
want make publicly visible.
now everything's been a secured entourage grady and now when I go off to sales
...contacts.
I can still login to sales force but notice I get this as your alien
We get this forgot your password or I can use as your...
Now because I'm...to add your ad
it will do a little bit of the dance if we watch the urls where it's going to go okay
you're logged in legal...sales force how tenet.
Provides your resume then I told you don't be don't be
dismayed demos with.
Thankful chasing dissing jinx...whatever.
Can't dance yes okay I...you we don't support click once
in the web that was another technology so it's click twice right so
I was able to do that dance with single sign on and it went off to measure
...found it and now...back...now?
There's one.
Thing there though I don't really want to be asked about the single signed the other thing...
I got single sign...fix let me solve that for so, you know, it's kind of weird to throw up a.
Throw up a login page and leave a button at the bottom for single sign
up it's not really that weird but it might be redundant in some cases so what
we're going to do is we're going to configure sales force to remove that.
So, this log into sales force.
That's probably microsoft online.
It's up there and it's.
Okay, and, I'm going to the select...the room, yeah.
Okay, and, now we're going to go into the setup area and
...area is where all the configuration inside of sales
...platform takes place you can see it's
pretty pretty complicated kind of old-fashioned but it works.
I'm going to configure that might domain thing we talked about earlier that had to do
with branding in my custom domain and I've got a setting down here at
the bottom for my authentication service that we've set up and simply unclear
king that login page check box saving
will now prevent that login page from showing up so what is log out here.
And, then steve.
Since the land we...the pleasure of have this blow up again sure why
It's not going to blow up modern technology.
All right so we'll go in here will click for a bug will go and,
actually...that happen that happen to quick
...in...that quick I was happy with that...
Right so you can kinda see...the slowdown phone time and
you can see on the top of did the redirects and the single sign having as the in
this case we're saying for this particular app we don't necessarily
...throw up the login page so, that's pretty cool I mean think about all the services we just consumed
here the productivity on how you were able to consume all of that and
the customizations we did with sales force so let me jump
out he gets a pretty cool demo anything there's a lot of stuff consumed in there there's,
there's some stuff that we didn't show you...the single sign...set up you know,
once you get that setup you can bang these things out like crazy.
And, we'll show you some links at the end so just...quickly because it is build you
are developers you might want to build one of these own connected services and I just want
to do a quick teaser into these so-if you want-to author them well that's
...sdk that we made available today that you can download and work with
a visual studio twenty fifteen rc to be able to build your own
connect services who would build one
...any service that has unique configurations any service that you want to
be able to have developers consume very easily just like we did was sales
...it was rocket science...first to be fair I mean they've a lot of
...features out so we don't know anything about it I didn't want to know anything about
...I just wanted to work and we learned it was very cool the
more we learn the more we looked back going wow that's actually pretty elegant pretty coolbut,
the learning curve
was pretty steep to get to the first point we want to
have developers have this per guests progressive learning experience
...first thing is shut off authentication just get to the good stuff now go back and
secure which we don't get to here because we have features like
connected services you can actually get a secure app up-front and then go back
investigative and,
by the way if you are interested the sales force connect others is
open-source so you can look at the code...how we did certain things see,
you know, what you might be able to steal from that I think we're pretty generous license on it so those
...you instill...borrower...would use leveraged and this is one of the things that
we worked early on is when we wanted to do this we want to use the salesperson implementation as
a reference implementation so again the kudos to our guys and fargo
they've been doing this work I it's very cool be able to see and very easy to
...a lot of functionality...easy but it's very clear what it's doing anyway so you can build
these just wrapping up we certainly want have connected services to enabled
the breadth and services that are out there we didn't want to be a one-size-fits-all we
wanted to support configuring
the service and the project which is what modern services required
...we wanted to help guide you with the next steps give you ownership
of the code we want to retire I like to joke retire mc hammer and they can't touch
this style coding we want to work with your code and this is what we want to be
doing more so in visual studio tooling and in fact I'd love to talk
to more about the kind of projects that you're doing and, of course we didn't want this to be
...to microsoft want to embrace third parties and there's no better third-party to embrace
than sales force so big hug?
And, for references ...references on the connected services information
And, of course information on developers sales force.
And, there's some info-on us...do again want to give out in addition to our
...development team...built this connected service and,
the correct service extension by the sales was going
...is tanner lindsay and land desk for letting us have their code
literally have their code understand what they were doing see the challenges that they were having
...be able to use that to figure out how do we make better tooling and,
there's some info...for tanner and I gotta say he was he
...he saw the video he was like I wish I had this months
...quick plugs so come downstairs...on the first-floor you'll see
...you're going for food we have these little things called quick starts.
And, if you finish the quick start which is basically just kind of walking through
the walk through that is part of the connected service you'll get this cool
...that is like so is apollo docking with sales force
and microsoft clo and...saying on the back that's pretty cool so come on,
down and try that out there's always one so that
we will say thank you and I appreciate you guys coming...was to graphs and questions and slot.
...get...consumer services and of course there's
...evaluate please yes please we do we those we appreciate them and,
thanks.